CHIBUOKEM EGBUCHULAM FRONTEND DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled frontend developer with over 3 years of experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, and VueJS. I enjoy creating user-friendly interfaces that are visually appealing and easy to use. My strong collaborative skills enable me to work efficiently with other developers, designers, and stakeholders. I am committed to constantly improving my skills and staying up-to-date with the latest front-end development trends to deliver exceptional code and user experiences.

Past Projects

ChitChat - Social Media Web App

- Developed a social media web application that allows users to create posts, like, and comment on them.
- Used Firebase Authentication, Firestore Database and Firebase Storage for backend services.
- Implemented user profile and avatar features, enabling users to view profiles and change their avatars.
- Integrated Firebase SDKs into the application, making API calls to fetch user-generated content and store media files
- Tools used: Reactjs, Chakra UI, React Icons, Firebase, vercel, etc

Github Repo Live Link

Project: GitHub Profile-Vue

- Built a Vue.js application that allows users to search for and view GitHub profiles
- Utilised the GitHub API to fetch user data and display it in a responsive UI
- Created components for different parts of the UI, including the search bar and user profile card
- Deployed the application using GitHub Pages
- Tools used: Vue.js, Vue router, Axios, GitHub API, GitHub Pages, etc

Github Repo Live Link

The Nail Boutique - Luxury Nail Salon

- Collaborated with two other individuals to develop the Nail Boutique application, together, we were responsible for coding the site
- Developed a responsive and user-friendly web application using modern front-end technologies
- Created a modular and reusable codebase that promotes maintainability and scalability.
- Achieved a high level of functionality and user experience without the use of a back-end platform.
- Demonstrated our ability to work collaboratively and see a project through from ideation to deployment.
- Tools used: Reactjs, Context API Material-UI, styled-components etc

Github Repo Live Link

Contact



Email

chibuokemegbuchulam egmail.com



Profile Links

in **Linkedin**



Portfolio Website

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Computer programming and coding
- Problem-solving
- Multitasking
- Attention to detail

Technical Skills

- HTML5, CSS3
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ReactJs
- VueJs
- Firebase
- SASS
- Styled-Components
- REST APIs
- Version control tool -Git, Github, BitBucket
- TailwindCSS
- Material UI
- Figma, Photoshop
- Chakra UI
- Jira
- SEO

Work History

2021 -PRESENT

Frontend Developer (Remote)

Ascendancy (Lagos, Nigeria)

- Write highly maintainable, solid code for software system, forming core framework and earning consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version
- Adjust design parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features
- Collaborate with clients to define solution requirements, accounting for applicable development variables
- Develop new user-facing features using ReactJs with consideration to boosting performance
- Translate designs and wireframes built in Figma into highquality code
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability

01/2016 -12/2020

Information Technology Instructor

SouthPointRoyal School (Edo, Nigeria)

- Trained students on basic computer software fundamentals
- · Recommended software improvement for school website
- Maintained and improved the e-learning facility

Education

2008 -2013

Federal University of Technology Owerri, Imo State, Nigeria

Bachelor of Engineering Degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Certification

04/2022 -06/2023

AltSchool Africa

Remote Frontend Engineering Program.

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and frontend development while simultaneously developing projects with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Reactjs, and Vuejs.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with other remote developers.

Other Projects:

- Github-Profile-React
 - o Github Repo
 - Live Link
- Surftweb
 - o Github Repo
 - Live Link